Preliminary Guide to the Africa News Service (Durham, N.C.) Leroy T. Walker Africa News Service Archive, 1952-1998 and undated (bulk 1952-1994)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Preliminary Container List For Accession 1997-0086 (Box 361)
  - Filed Clippings, 1990s (Box 24)
    - Latin America, U.S. Groups (Box 24)
  - United Nations Publications, 1960s-1970s (Box 25)
    - African issues (Box 25)
  - State Department Publications, 1970s-1980s (Box 26)
    - Foreign Agents Registration Act - Directories of agents of foreign governments operating in the United States. (Box 26)
  - Published Congressional Hearings, 1960s-1970s (Box 27)
    - African issues (Box 27)
  - Published Congressional Hearings, 1960s-1970s (Box 28)
    - African issues (Box 28)
  - Newsletters and Pamphlets, 1970s-1980s (Box 29)
    - African issues (Box 29)
  - Newsletters and Pamphlets, 1970-1980s (Box 30)
    - African issues (Box 30)
- Preliminary Container List For Accession 2000-0208 (Box 30)
  - Clippings file (Box 1)
    - U.S. Foreign Relations Clinton Foreign Policy: 1991-1992 (Box 1)
    - U.S. Foreign Relations Africa: Clinton Policy: 1992 (Box 1)
    - U.S. Foreign Relations Africa: Clinton Policy: 1992- (Box 1)
    - U.S. Foreign Relations Clinton Foreign Policy: 1993- (Box 1)
    - U.S. Foreign Relations Africa: Clinton Policy: 1993 (Box 1)
    - U.S. Foreign Relations Africa: Clinton Policy: 1994- (Box 1)
- Preliminary Container List For Accession 2001-0156 (Box 1)
  - Contents of box 1: (Box 1)
    - UN Report on Namibia from South African embassy, Sept. 1980 (Box 1)
    - Report on urban development in South Africa (Box 1)
    - Industrial Laws of South Africa (Box 1)
  - Contents of box 2, early 1970s: (Box 2)
    - Ecumenical Commission papers on Vietnam and South Africa (Box 2)
    - U.S. church and corporate statements on South Africa (Box 2)
    - Center for the Study of Power and Peace reports (Box 2)
    - Corporate Information Center material on church and business investment in Southern Africa (Box 2)
    - Student involvement -- material on conference at Duke (Box 2)
    - Information from South African government including brochures on African urban life (Box 2)
  - Contents of box 3, early 1970s: (Box 3)
    - Articles and analysis on apartheid and racial reform (Box 3)
    - News and reports on South Africa and world policy toward South Africa (Box 3)
    - Protest news (Box 3)
  - Contents of box 4, 1966-1974: (Box 4)
    - Church and banking -- protest and discussion related to South Africa (Box 4)
    - Regional church and missionary information (Box 4)
    - UN apartheid papers (Box 4)
    - Sharpeville 10 year memorial materials (Box 4)
    - Copies of newspapers (Box 4)
      - Dimension (Christian paper), 1970-1972 (Box 4)
      - Some issues of Progress, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - Other religious and progressive publications, 1967-1971 (Box 4)
  - Contents of box 5, 1960-early 1970s: (Box 5)
    - Religious and progressive publications, 1967-1971 (Box 5)
    - Liberation movement materials (Box 5)
    - Materials from other organizations working against apartheid (Box 5)
    - Collected informational files on Southern Africa (Box 5)
    - Student organizing material, 1964-1965 (Box 5)
    - Reports and correspondence, 1960-1970 (Box 5)
    - South Africa Airways demonstrations, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Information on other boycotts and demonstrations (Box 5)
  - Contents of box 6, 1964-1970: (Box 6)
    - Student information (Box 6)
    - Information on sports boycotts of South Africa (Box 6)
    - General anti-apartheid media and materials particularly on racial classifications (Box 6)
    - South Africa news updates (Box 6)
    - South African government-provided information (Box 6)
  - Contents of box 7, 1960-1974: (Box 7)
    - Anti-apartheid analysis and news materials (Box 7)
      Religious materials, student materials, collection of government-issued reports, statistics, cultural issues, legal and judicial information, collections of news clippings.
  - Contents of box 8, 1965-1973: (Box 8)
    - Topical folders including health, prisons, refugees, specific cases, individuals, activism. (Box 8)
    - Labor issues (Box 8)
    - South African social structure and concerns (Box 8)
    - Black Attitudes (Box 8)
    - Foreign Trade with South Africa -- Regional and country information (Box 8)
  - Contents of box 9, 1969-1975: (Box 9)
    - Foreign Trade with South Africa -- Regional and country information (Box 9)
    - Political topics including visa denial, police action (Box 9)
    - UN documents on general apartheid and student protest (Box 9)
    - Africa Institute materials (Box 9)
    - Programs for literacy and health (Box 9)
    - Athletic and cultural information (Box 9)
    - Industry-specific economic information, including cosmetics, iron and steel, mining, heavy machinery (Box 9)
    - Labor issues -- training of workers, unskilled labor (Box 9)
  - Contents of box 10, 1968-1988: (Box 10)
    - Statistics and analysis about wages and labor (Box 10)
    - Industry-specific economic information, including oil, sugar, wool, electrical, fertilizer, food, glass, engineering, mining, pharmaceutical. (Box 10)
    - Labor issues -- teachers, unions, Wages and Productivity Association, servants (Box 10)
    - Foreign trade with South Africa -- regional and country information (Box 10)
    - Angola-South Africa relations (4 folders) (Box 10)
  - Contentts of box 11, 1952-1973: (Box 11)
    - National Union of South African Students (NUSAS) information (Box 11)
    - University Christian Movement information (Box 11)
    - News clippings, pamphlets, and books (Box 11)
    - South African churches reaction to World Council of Churches action 1970-1972 (Box 11)
    - U.S. and Canadian church protest and dialogue on apartheid (Box 11)
    - Information on Tom Mboya (Box 11)
  - Contents of box 12, 1952-1974: (Box 12)
    - Labor files (Box 12)
      - African bargaining rights and trade unions (Box 12)
      - Government's labor legislation and policies (Box 12)
      - International pressure (Box 12)
      - Job reservation (Box 12)
      - Industries: building, chemical, clothing, agriculture, commerce, construction, electrical, glass, hotel, iron and steel, motor, printing, rail, mining. (Box 12)
      - Workers: Coloured and Indian, auto mechanics, dockworkers, doctors and nurses, domestic servants, farm labor, government employees, prison labor, migrant labor, strikes. (Box 12)
  - Contents of box 13, 1961-1976: (Box 13)
    - Labor files (Box 13)
      - Strikes -- Miners and other industries (Box 13)
      - Labor shortages -- Immigration, Government Views, Proposed Solutions (Box 13)
    - Political Files (Box 13)
      - Bannings and detention, (3 folders) (Box 13)
      - Removals and pass laws (Box 13)
      - Censorship (Box 13)
      - Congress Movement (Box 13)
      - Vorster speeches (Box 13)
      - Legal aid programs (Box 13)
      - Legal system (Box 13)
      - Petty apartheid (Box 13)
      - Police and prisons (Box 13)
  - Contents of box 14, 1969-1977: (Box 14)
    - Canning and beverage industry information (Box 14)
    - Labor Shortage -- business views (Box 14)
    - Bantu magazine, Dec. 1969-Sept. 1977 (Box 14)
  - Contents of box 15, 1972-1986: (Box 15)
    - Bantu magazine, Jan. 1972-Nov. 1972 (Box 15)
    - Fiat Lux magazine, Feb. 1979-Oct. 1986 (Box 15)
  - Contents of box 16, 1968-1980: (Box 16)
    - Fiat Lux magazine, Jan. 1977-Dec. 1978 (Box 16)
    - Issue opinion journal, 1976, 1980 (Box 16)
    - Clippings and media material, (6 folders) (Box 16)
  - Contents of box 17, 1967-1976: (Box 17)
    - Clippings and media material, (14 folders) (Box 17)
  - Contents of box 18, 1967-1976: (Box 18)
    - Clippings and media material, (14 folders) (Box 18)
  - Contents of box 19, 1966-1967 and undated: (Box 19)
    - Clippings and media material, (19 folders) (Box 19)
  - Contents of box 20, 1952-1970: (Box 20)
    - Labor -- including Trade Union Council of South Africa materials (Box 20)
    - News about arms sales to South Africa (Box 20)
    - Afrikaaner politicians info -- Vorster and Verwoerd (Box 20)
    - "Moral Conflict in South Africa" Pax Romana (Box 20)
    - Articles on South Africa, (3 folders) (Box 20)
    - International Labor Conference report on apartheid (Box 20)
    - ANC statement by Oliver Tambo (Box 20)
    - Christian Council "Message to the People of South Africa" (Box 20)
    - Reports on prison conditions (Box 20)
    - Indian South Africans (Box 20)
  - Contents of box 21, 1951-1975: (Box 21)
    - Indian South Africans (Box 21)
    - Indian Religion in South Africa (Box 21)
    - Immigrants to South Africa (Box 21)
    - South Africa Social Files (Box 21)
      - Auto Safety (Box 21)
      - Crime (Box 21)
      - Culture (Box 21)
      - General (Box 21)
      - Drugs (Box 21)
    - Art and Apartheid (Box 21)
    - South African Education (Box 21)
    - Medicine (Box 21)
    - Banning of Kennis Van Die Aand (Box 21)
    - World Image of South Africa (Box 21)
    - Banning of The Guardian (Box 21)
    - Christian Century articles (Box 21)
    - South Africa Political Files (Box 21)
      - UN Documents on Repression, (2 folders) (Box 21)
      - Repressive Legislation (Box 21)
      - Schlebusch (Box 21)
  - Contents of box 22, 1952-1978 (Box 22)
    - South Africa Political Files (Box 22)
      - Verligte Action (Box 22)
      - UN Documents on Trials and Political Prisoners (Box 22)
        - 1973- (Box 22)
        - 1964-1967 (Box 22)
        - 1968-1969 (Box 22)
        - 1970-1972 (Box 22)
    - Publications on Africa and South Africa (Box 22)
  - Contents of box 23, 1961-1978: (Box 23)
    - Publications on Africa and South Africa (Box 23)
  - Contents of box 24, 1935-1975: (Box 24)
    - Publications on Africa and South Africa (Box 24)
  - Contents of box 25, 1965-1989: (Box 25)
    - Publications on Africa and South Africa (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings and Reports on Southern Africa, (6 folders) (Box 25)
  - Contents of box 26, 1970-1986: (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings and Reports on Southern Africa, (1 folder) (Box 26)
    - Southern Africa Committee Correspondence, (8 folders) (Box 26)
  - Contents of box 27, 1965-1975: (Box 27)
    - Southern Africa Committee Correspondence, (10 folders) (Box 27)
    - Clippings on Rhodesia (Box 27)
    - The New Yorker articles on South Africa (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous articles, papers, and reports on South Africa (Box 27)
    - ANC publications (Box 27)
    - Newspaper clippings on Southern Africa, (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous articles, papers, and reports on Southern Africa, (3 folders) (Box 27)
  - Contents of box 28, 1966-1975: (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous articles, papers, and reports on Southern Africa (Box 28)
    - Zimbabwe files (Box 28)
      - Censorship (Box 28)
      - Centre Party (Box 28)
      - Churches (Box 28)
      - U.C.B.W.M. Bulletins (Box 28)
      - Comments (Box 28)
      - Pamphlets and Articles, (2 folders) (Box 28)
      - Trials and Political Prisoners (Box 28)
      - Tribal Trust (Box 28)
      - Violence (Box 28)
      - White Settlers (Box 28)
    - Portugal in Africa (Box 28)
    - MPLA (Angola liberation movement) statement (Box 28)
    - Frelimo (Mozambique liberation front) (Box 28)
    - Mozambique, (2 folders) (Box 28)
  - Contents of box 29, 1965-1970: (Box 29)
    - Rhodesia (Box 29)
      - Who Rules Rhodesia? pamphlet (Box 29)
      - Sanctions (Box 29)
      - American business in Rhodesia (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous material on Rhodesia (Box 29)
    - Friends of Zimbabwe (Box 29)
    - Zimbabwe Review (Box 29)
    - Rhodesian Clippings, 1970 (Box 29)
    - Rhodesia (Box 29)
  - Contents of legal size box 30, 1965-1969: (Box 30)
    - NUSAS material, (6 folders) (Box 30)
    - Education in South Africa (Box 30)
    - University Christian Movement material (Box 30)
    - Christian and student movement material, (1 of 4 folders) (Box 30)
  - Contents of legal size box 31, 1966-1986: (Box 31)
    - Christian and student movement material, (3 of 4 folders) (Box 31)
    - South Africa: Pol: Bannings and Detention: General Clippings, pre-1973 (Box 31)
    - Trade Unionism lecture references (Box 31)
    - [French reaction to arms sales to South Africa] (in French) (Box 31)
    - South Africa Fact Sheet -- NCC (Box 31)
    - Indian South Africans (Box 31)
    - Publications on Africa and South Africa (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings and Reports on Southern Africa (Box 31)
    - Southern Africa Committee Correspondence (Box 31)
    - [Miscellaneous Clippings and Reports] (Box 31)
    - Zimbabwe News (ZANU) (Box 31)
    - Rhodesia (Box 31)
  - Contents of oversize folder: (Box 31)
    - Changing Africa map, 1993 (Opaperfolder 1, Box 31)
Materials Cataloged Separately
The following titles have been cataloged individually by title in the Duke University Libraries catalog. They have been removed from the collection and are shelved separately as serials.
2020 Vision
Action for Children
Africa Analysis: 1986-1994
Africa Business and Economic Review
Africa Insider
Africa Newsfile
Alarm
All Africa Press Service
AJME News
ANC Weekly News Briefing
Angola Update
ANGOP News Bulletin (Agencia Angola Press)
Article 19
Baobab Notes
Baobab Press
Bank Check Quarterly
BBC Script Service for Africa
BBC Summary of World Broadcasts
CFM News and Notes (Committee for a Free Mozambique)
Corporate Examiner
Codel News
CSIS Africa Report
Democracy Report
Developing World Monitor
Development Communication Report
Easa
Ecoafrica
Eritrea in Struggle
Eritrean Relief Committee Newsletter
Eritrea Update
Facts and Reports (Southern Africa)
First Call for Children (UNICEF)
Foreign Affairs Report
Fourth World Bulletin
Friends of Ethiopia Newsletter
Human Rights Perspectives
IDAF Briefing Paper
IDAF Focus
IDAF News Notes
IMF Memorandum
Indian Ocean Newsletter
International Council for Adult Education News
International Documents Review
International Newsbriefing on Namibia
Internewsletter
Israeli Foreign Affairs
Juluka
Kenya News Direct
La Leitre: Recontre et Development (or La Lettre: Recontre et Development)
Land Tenure Center Newsletter
Liberia Watch/Liberia Diaspora
Link: US Ties to South Africa
Market Southeast
Middle East Economic Survey
Mozambique Information Office News Review (UK)
Mozambique Support Network Newsletter
Mozambique Update
Namibia Communications Centre
Namibia Information Service
Namibia Newsletter
Namibia Report
News from Ethiopia
Newsletter on the Oil Embargo Against South Africa
NGO Networker
North African News
Organizing Notes
Press Releases of the Permanent Mission of the People's Republic of Angola to the United States
Publication of the Mozambique Information Agency (with various titles)
Recon
Safrican News
Saharan Peoples Support Committee Letter
Saspost
Solidarity News Service
SA Dialogue
Southern Africa Dossier
South Africa Embassy Letter and Fact Sheet
South Africa Foundation Review
South African Education Program Newsletter
South African Labour News
South African Pressclips
Southern Africa
Southern Africa Development News
Southern Africa Report, 1988-1997
SouthScan
Standard Bank Economic Review (South Africa)
Statistical News Release
Sub-Saharan Monitor
Sudan Democratic Gazette
Sudan Monitor
Sudan Update
Thursday's Child (UNICEF)
Transafrica Forum
Transafrica News Report
Tunisian Digest
Update
UPI Advance
Washington Notes on Africa
Washington Report on Africa
Western Sahara Campaign News
World Bank News
X-Ray on Current Affairs in South Africa